http://www.cityandguilds.com/help/privacy-statement

CloseCity & Guilds GroupPressWorldwide officesChoose your locationAfricaCaribbean and The AmericasEast Asia (ASEAN and Greater China)EuropeIndia and NepalIrelandMiddle EastPacificScotlandSouth AsiaUKWales
Search everything
Find course / Qualification
Find Centre
I'm a:
Centre
Employer
Learner
Other
Search everything
Search everything
Search the site:
Search
Find course / Qualification
Find a course or qualification
I'm looking for:
Search
Find Centre
Find a centre
Near me:
Offering:
Search
Covid-19End-point assessmentFunctional skillsWales, Scotland and Northern Ireland2020-21 Adaptations guidanceOur offerCentresLearnersEmployersQualificationsQualifications explainedApprenticeshipsStandardsOn-programme learningEPA serviceSuccess storiesBecome an IEPAGet-to-GatewayDeliver an apprenticeshipApprenticeship fundingBecome an apprenticeEvents and webinarsContact usTechnicalsDeliver Technical QualificationsStudy Technical QualificationsSubject areasResources and supportEvents and webinarsTechnicals Case StudiesFAQsContact usT LevelsEmployersProvidersEventsQualification deliveryCentre developmentExams and AdminDigital CredentialsFunding for trainingOffer our qualificationsInternationalAfricaEast Asia, ASEAN and Greater ChinaCaribbean and the AmericasIndia and NepalMiddle East and North AfricaPacificSouth AsiaCase StudiesContactEventsCPD TrainingTechnical AdvisorsHelpHelp for centresHelp for learnersHelp for employersHelp for associatesFeedback and ComplaintsHelp for centresHelp for learnersHelp for employersHelp for associatesFeedback and ComplaintsCovid-19End-point assessmentFunctional skillsWales, Scotland and Northern Ireland2020-21 Adaptations guidanceOur offerCentresLearnersEmployersQualificationsQualifications explainedApprenticeshipsStandardsOn-programme learningEPA serviceSuccess storiesBecome an IEPAGet-to-GatewayDeliver an apprenticeshipApprenticeship fundingBecome an apprenticeEvents and webinarsContact usTechnicalsDeliver Technical QualificationsStudy Technical QualificationsSubject areasResources and supportEvents and webinarsTechnicals Case StudiesFAQsContact usT LevelsEmployersProvidersEventsQualification deliveryCentre developmentExams and AdminDigital CredentialsFunding for trainingOffer our qualificationsInternationalAfricaEast Asia, ASEAN and Greater ChinaCaribbean and the AmericasIndia and NepalMiddle East and North AfricaPacificSouth AsiaCase StudiesContactEventsCPD TrainingTechnical AdvisorsHelpHelp for centresHelp for learnersHelp for employersHelp for associatesFeedback and ComplaintsCity & Guilds GroupPressWorldwide OfficesAfricaCaribbean and The AmericasEast AsiaEuropeIrelandMiddle EastPacificScotlandSouth AsiaSouth East AsiaUK
Home6142988E-FCB9-4B23-B4F3-1A46280E2C37>Help6142988E-FCB9-4B23-B4F3-1A46280E2C37>Privacy Policy6142988E-FCB9-4B23-B4F3-1A46280E2C37>
Privacy Policy
Introduction
The City & Guilds Group is committed to data security and the fair and transparent processing of personal data. This privacy policy (Policy) sets out how City & Guilds, as a member of the City & Guilds Group, treats the personal data of Website visitors in compliance with applicable data protection law, in particular the General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (GDPR) and the UK Data Protection Act 2018 (DPA).
You can read more about the City & Guilds Group companies at www.cityandguildsgroup.com
If you are visiting our Website, please read this Policy carefully as it contains important information on who we are, how and why we collect, store, use and share your personal data (process), your rights in relation to your personal data, how to contact us, and how to contact supervisory authorities in the event that you would like to report a concern about the way in which we process your personal data.
Who are we?
City & Guilds owns and operates www.cityandguilds.com (Website). This Policy, together with our Website terms of use and any other documents referred to in them, sets out the basis on which City & Guilds processes personal data via our Website, or in connection with the provision of information, products, and services to you.
For the purposes of the GDPR and DPA, City & Guilds is the ‘controller’ of personal data processed via our Website or in connection the provision information, products, and services to you.
The City and Guilds of London Institute is a charity incorporated by Royal Charter, with registered charity number 312832 (England and Wales) and SC039576 (Scotland). Our registered address is Giltspur House, 5-6 Giltspur Street, London, EC1A 9DE (City & Guilds, we, us, or our).
If you have any queries about this Policy, the way in which City & Guilds processes your personal data, or about exercising any of your rights, you may send an email to gdpr@cityandguilds.com or write to Data Protection, City & Guilds, Giltspur House, 5-6 Giltspur Street, London, EC1A 9DE.
What personal data do we collect?
We may collect and process the following personal data:
Personal data you provide to us:
If you:
complete a form on our Website;
complete a survey;
correspond with us by phone, email, or in writing;
attend an event organised by us;
complete a course or e-learning module offered by us;
report a problem;
sign up to receive our communications;
create an account with us; or
enter into a contract with us to receive products and/or services,
we may collect your name, email address, postal address, telephone number and/or job role.
Personal data we collect about you
If you visit our Website, we may automatically collect the following personal data and/or information:
technical information, including the internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, login information, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform; and
information about your visit to our Website, such as the products and/or services you searched for and view, page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page.
Personal data we receive from other sources
We may also receive personal data about you if you use any of the other websites which we, or another member of the City & Guilds Group, operate or the other services and/or products which we, or another member of the City & Guilds Group, provide.
If you are a tutor, apprentice, or learner, we may also receive personal data about you from a related centre, customer, employer, employer provider, or training provider, when they register to receive products and/or services from us.
Personal data about other people
If you provide personal data to us about any person other than yourself, such as your relatives, next of kin, advisers or suppliers, you must ensure that they understand how their personal data will be processed, and that they have given their permission for you to disclose it to us and for you to allow us, and our third party service providers, to process it.
Special category data
In exceptional circumstances, we may also collect and/or be provided with special category data, such as data about your physical or mental health or condition. For example, we may collect and/or be provided with special category data to enable us to administer requests for reasonable adjustments, or in relation to an investigation, complaint, or appeal. Such data should only be collected and/or provided to us if you have provided your explicit consent or if we are otherwise permitted to receive and process it under the GDPR and/or DPA (including as set out below).
How do we use your personal data?
When we ask you to supply us with personal data we will make it clear whether the personal data we are asking for must be supplied so that we can provide any products and/or services to you, or whether the supply of any personal data we ask for is optional.
Contract performance: we may process your personal data to fulfil a contract, or to take steps linked to a contract, including to:
provide products and/or services to you;
communicate with you in relation to the provision of contracted products and/or services; and
provide you with administrative support such as account creation, security, and responding to issues.
Legitimate interests: we may process your personal data where it is necessary to pursue our, or third parties’, legitimate interests, including to:
communicate with you in relation to any issues, complaints, or disputes;
develop, improve and deliver marketing and advertising for products and/or services offered by us or another member of the City & Guilds Group;
arrange for a digital credential to be issued to you when you have successfully completed a course or e-learning module, attended an event, or in recognition of an achievement;
improve the quality of experience when you interact with our products and/or services, including testing the performance and customer experience of our Website;
perform analytics on sales/marketing data, determining the effectiveness of promotional campaigns; and
prevent and detect crime and/or assist with the apprehension or prosecution of offenders.
We may also process your personal data in pursuance of our legitimate interests to provide you with newsletters, surveys, or information about our awards and events, offers, and promotions, related to products and/or services offered by us or another member of the City & Guilds Group which may be of interest to you. Where you do receive such marketing communications from us, you may change your preferences or unsubscribe from marketing communications at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link in an email from us.
Note that you have the right to object to the processing of your personal data on the basis of legitimate interests as set out below, under the heading Your rights.
Where required by law:  we may also process your personal data if required by law.
Consent: we may process your special category data when we have obtained your explicit consent to do so.
With respect to special category data, we may also process such data if necessary for reasons of substantial public interest, including for the prevention or detection of unlawful acts or in compliance with, or to assist third parties to comply with, any regulatory requirements relating to the investigation of unlawful acts, dishonesty or malpractice.
Who do we share your personal data with?
We may share your personal data with trusted third party service providers, including:
legal and other professional advisers, consultants, and professional experts;
service providers contracted to us in connection with our Website or provision of information, products and services, such as providers of IT services and customer relationship management services;
·our digital credential partner Credly Inc, based in the US, which owns and manages www.credly.com and
analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our Website.
We will ensure that there is a contract in place with such third party service providers, which includes obligations in relation to the confidentiality, security, and lawful processing of any personal data shared with them, and which upholds your rights and freedoms with respect to personal data.
Where a third party recipient is located outside the European Economic Area, we will ensure that the transfer of personal data is protected by appropriate safeguards, including EU – US privacy shield participation, or by the use of standard data protection clauses adopted or approved by the European Commission, where the Commission does not believe that the country has adequate data protection laws.
We may also share your personal data with other members of the City & Guilds Group, including members of the City & Guilds Group based both inside and outside of the European Economic Area.
We may also share personal data (including any special category data) with law enforcement or other authorities or agencies if required by law or where we otherwise deem it necessary in pursuance of our legitimate interests. This may include, without being limited to, responding to requests for information from such authorities or agencies, or sharing information with them in connection with our quality assurance processes, investigations, complaints, or appeals.
You should be aware that, where personal data is shared with a public authority, it will become subject to the Freedom of Information Act 2000 (FOIA) and may potentially fall within the scope of any future FOIA request made to such public authority.
How long will we keep your personal data?
We will keep your personal data for the duration of any contract between us. Thereafter, we will keep personal data in order to:
provide information about your relationship with City & Guilds;
respond to any questions, complaints or claims made by you, on your behalf or about you;
comply with any relevant third party record retention requirements (e.g. those of a regulator); and
comply with any contractual, legal, audit, and other regulatory requirements, or any orders from competent courts or authorities.
We will also keep personal data relating to our quality assurance processes, investigations, appeals and complaints, in order to comply with applicable contractual, legal, audit and other regulatory requirements, or any orders from competent courts or authorities.
City & Guilds keeps personal data for no longer than as is necessary for the above purposes.
How do we protect your personal data?
We take all reasonable steps to ensure that both we and our third party service providers protect your personal data. This includes ensuring that our staff are aware of their information security obligations, providing training, and limiting access to your personal data to staff who have a genuine business need to know.
We also take reasonable steps to protect your personal data from loss or destruction and have procedures in place to deal with any suspected data security breach. We will notify you and any applicable regulator of a suspected data security breach where we are legally required to do so.
Furthermore, our project management and change control process includes structured assessment of information security and data privacy risks. This process aims to ensure that all proposed system changes of City & Guilds from time to time fully align with the GDPR and good practice to uphold data subjects’ rights and freedoms with respect to personal data.
Note that where you as a Website visitor have a username or password (or other identification information) which enables you to access certain services or parts of our Website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share passwords with anyone.
Note that unfortunately the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal data transmitted to our Website; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your personal data, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.
Your rights
Under the GDPR, you have various rights with respect to our processing of your personal data:
Right to Access
You have the right to request a copy of the personal data that we hold about you by contacting us at the email or postal address given below. Please include with your request information that will enable us to verify your identity. We will respond within 1 month of request. Please note that there are exceptions to this right. We may be unable to make all data available to you if, for example, making the data available to you would reveal personal data about another person, if we are legally prevented from disclosing such data, if there is no basis for your request, or if your request is excessive.
Right to rectification
We aim to keep your personal data accurate, current and complete. We encourage you to contact us using the contact details provided below to let us know if any of your personal data is not accurate or changes, so that we can keep your personal data up-to-date.
Right to erasure
You have the right to request the deletion of your personal data where, for example, the personal data is no longer necessary for the purposes for which it was collected, where you withdraw your consent to processing, where there is no overriding legitimate interest for us to continue to process your personal data, or your personal data has been unlawfully processed. If you would like to request that your personal data be erased, please contact us using the contact details provided below.
Right to object
In certain circumstances, you have the right to object to the processing of your personal data where, for example, your personal data is being processed on the basis of legitimate interests and there is no overriding legitimate interest for us to continue to process your personal data, or if your data is being processed for direct marketing purposes. If you would like to object to the processing of your personal data, please contact us using the contact details provided below.
Right to restrict processing
In certain circumstances, you have the right to request that we restrict the further processing of your personal data. This right arises where, for example, you have queried the accuracy of the personal data we hold about you and we are verifying the personal data, you have objected to processing based on legitimate interests and we are considering whether there are any overriding legitimate interests, or the processing is unlawful and you elect that processing is restricted rather than deleted. If you would like to make such request, please contact us using the contact details provided below.
Right to data portability
In certain circumstances, you have the right to request that some of your personal data is provided to you, or to another ‘controller’, in a commonly used, machine-readable format. This right arises where you have provided your personal data to us, the processing is based on consent or the performance of a contract, and processing is carried out by automated means. If you would like to make such request, please contact us using the contact details provided below.
Please note that the GDPR sets out exceptions to these rights. If we are unable to comply with your request due to an exception we will explain this to you in our response.
Contact
If you have any queries about this Policy, the way in which City & Guilds processes personal data via our Website, or about exercising any of your rights, you can send an email to gdpr@cityandguilds.com or write to Data Protection, City & Guilds, Giltspur House, 5-6 Giltspur Street, London, EC1A 9DE.
Complaints
If you believe that your data protection rights may have been breached, and we have been unable to resolve your concern, you may lodge a complaint with the applicable supervisory authority or seek a remedy through the courts. Please visit the UK Information Commissioner’s Office website for more information on how to report a concern.
Changes to our Policy
Any changes we may make to our Policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by email. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our Policy.
- Privacy Policy Version 4, 13 July 2020
HelpHelp for centresAbout centresReplacement certificatesPersonal learning recordSmartScreen helpWalled Garden help and supportFAQsHelp for learnersReplace and amend your certificateAbout coursesAbout qualificationsFAQsLearner privacy policyHelp for employersHelp for associatesAssociate vacanciesFeedback and Complaints
Tools and SupportWalled GardenSmartScreenLearning Assistante-volveEventsEmail UpdatesCity & Guilds Group websitesQuick linksHelp and supportDelivering Our QualificationsEmployer supportLearner supportNewsAbout usCareers at City & GuildsPressContact usContact our Quality teamsInternationalUK and Ireland officesWebsite feedbackFeedback on Products and ServicesSocial networksTerms of UsePrivacy PolicyAccessibilityCookies
